EarlyWatch Alert
21075820 - ERP
26.01.2026 - 01.02.2026
Confidential
Service Summary
2/163
1 Service Summary
-
This EarlyWatch Alert session detected issues that could
potentially affect your system. Please evaluate the
recommendations.
Alert Overview
-
Mainstream/extended maintenance/priority-one support (if offered) for your SAP product version has ended or will end
soon.
SAP HANA Database: The maintenance end for your HANA Database Support Package Stack is reached.
Gateway Access Control List sec_info is not effective. Well-known attacks may endager your system.
SAP Software on this system is outdated. Support with SAP Security Notes is no longer ensured.
SAP HANA database: User SYSTEM is active and valid.
SAP HANA database: Support Package has run out of security maintenance. Support with SAP Security Notes is no
longer ensured.
Users with critical authorizations, which allow to do anything in client 000
Users with critical authorizations, which allow to do anything in other client(s) than 000
Users with critical authorizations, which should not be used in production in other client(s) than 000
With the SAP kernel of your ABAP system the stability or consistency is at risk.
We found more than 30 ABAP dumps in your system.
SAP HANA database: Parameters are not set in accordance with the recommendation.
SAP HANA database: Number of Records reaches recommended limit.
SAP HANA database: Memory consumption of tables exceeds 50% of usable memory.
SAP HANA database: Consistency checks are scheduled without the global consistency check.
SAP HANA database: Few SAP HANA dumps occurred on your system.
Standard users have default passwords in other client(s) than 000
TMSADM exists in another client than 000
To provide feedback on the alerts, please use the 'Hide and Snooze Alert' functionality in the Solution Finder . You can hide
alerts if you consider them irrelevant or snooze them if the recommendations are already in implementation. The blog Hide
and Snooze SAP EarlyWatch Alerts explains how to use it and the required authorization "Manage Alert(s)" in SAP
EarlyWatch Alert.
Note: If you send SAP EarlyWatch Alert data to SAP, this report can be viewed in "SAP for Me" . One of the benefits of
using SAP EarlyWatch Alert Workspace is receiving proactive alerts that are calculated in the workspace only and are not
available in a Solution Manager Do not miss any important findings: subscribe to notifications with just a few clicks on
Notification Activation . For detailed configuration options, read this Best Practices blog.
How to get access to the SAP EarlyWatch Alert apps is explained in SAP Note 2520319 . The following link to the SAP
EarlyWatch Alert Reports app always opens up the latest report for this system. Similarly, this link to the SAP EarlyWatch
Alert Dashboard shows you the analytical dashboard for this system. Specific links to analytical detail pages in SAP
EarlyWatch Alert Workspace are included in the respective sections in this report.
The EWA Status App is your entry point for analysis if you are missing the current data in EarlyWatch Alert apps.
Check Overview
-
Topic Rating Topic
Subtopic Rating Subtopic
Service Data Quality and Service Readiness
-
-
-
-
Sending EarlyWatch Alert of ERP
to SAP Backbone

EarlyWatch Alert
21075820 - ERP
26.01.2026 - 01.02.2026
Confidential
Service Summary
3/163
Topic Rating Topic
Subtopic Rating Subtopic
-
-
Configuring ERP for SAP Note
Assistant
-
-
Service Preparation of ERP
Software Configuration for ERP
-
-
-
-
SAP Application Release -
Maintenance Phases
-
-
Security Risk Due to Outdated
Support Packages
-
-
Database - Maintenance Phases
-
-
Operating System(s) -
Maintenance Phases
-
-
SAP Kernel Release
-
-
HANA Database Version for HRP
Hardware Capacity
-
-
Workload Distribution ERP
-
-
-
-
Workload by Application Module
-
-
DB Load Profile
Performance Overview ERP
-
-
SAP System Operating ERP
-
-
-
-
Availability based on Collector
Protocols
-
-
Program Errors (ABAP Dumps)
-
-
Update Errors
-
-
Table Reorganization
-
-
Critical Number Ranges
Security
-
-
-
-
System Recommendations
(HANA)
-
-
Maintenance Status of current
SAP HANA Database Revision
-
-
SAP HANA System Privilege
DATA ADMIN
-
-
SAP HANA Password Policy
-
-
SAP HANA Audit Trail
-
-
SAP HANA SQL Trace Level
-
-
SAP HANA Network Settings for
Internal Services
-
-
SAP HANA Network Settings for
System Replication
Communication (listeninterface)
-
-
Activation Status and Validity of
User SYSTEM
-
-
System Recommendations
(ABAP)
-
-
Age of Support Packages
-
-
Default Passwords of Standard
Users
-
-
Control of the Automatic Login
User SAP*
-
-
Protection of Passwords in
Database Connections
-
-
ABAP Password Policy
-
-
RFC Gateway Security
-
-
Message Server Security
-
-
Critical authorizations, which
allow to do anything

EarlyWatch Alert
21075820 - ERP
26.01.2026 - 01.02.2026
Confidential
Service Summary
4/163
Topic Rating Topic
Subtopic Rating Subtopic
-
-
Critical authorizations, which
should not be used in production
-
-
Critical authorizations, which
should only see very limited use
in production
Software Change and Transport Management of
ERP
-
-
-
-
Number of Changes
-
-
Emergency Changes
-
-
Failed Changes
Upgrade Planning
-
-
-
-
Compatibility Package Usage:
Information for SAP Solution
Manager
SAP HANA Database HRP
-
-
-
-
SAP HANA Stability and Alerts
-
-
SAP HANA Database
Configuration
-
-
SAP HANA Resource
Consumption
-
-
SAP HANA Workload and
Performance
-
-
Size and Growth
-
-
Administration
SAP NetWeaver Gateway
-
-
-
-
MetaData Cache Activation
-
-
Logging Configuration
-
-
Gateway Error Logs
-
-
Important Periodic Jobs
The check overview includes checks executed with a green result, which do not appear in the report.
Note: All recommendations in this report are based on our general experience. Test them before using them in your
production system. Note that EarlyWatch Alert is an automatic service.
Note: If you have any questions</B> about the accuracy of the checks in this report or the correct configuration of the SAP
EarlyWatch Alert service, create a customer case under component SV-SMG-SER-EWA.
Note: If you require any assistance in resolving concerns about your system performance or if you require a technical
analysis of other aspects of your system as highlighted in the report, please follow the instructions below:
Create a case using the Get Support application in SAP for Me ( KBA 1296527 ). Contact one of the administrators in your
company if your S-user ID does not have the required authorizations.
Within case creation, select the system. From the menu, choose:
- Product : Customer Project-Based Solution
- Component : insert required component (for example, if you wish to open a case on the topic 'performance', please use
component SV-PERF.)
If you need assistance, contact your local Customer Interaction Center (CIC) or SAP representative. Please refer to SAP
Note 560499 . For information about how to set the appropriate priority level, see SAP Note 67739 .
-
1.1 Performance Indicators for ERP
-
The following table shows the relevant performance indicators in various system areas.
Area
Indicators
Value
Trend
System Performance
Active Users (>400 steps)
148
-
Avg. Availability per Week
100 %

